Now I have to ask you,
have you ever been broke before?
That's a great question.
Have you ever been broke before?
Excuse me, sir, question for you.
So I haven't been broke, bro.
However, you know, when I was in college a
couple of years ago at the University of Texas,
I had maybe a couple thousand
dollars to my name from, you know,
working at Chick-fil-A when I was in high school.
Eventually I worked construction before I
went all in on the media business.
So I wasn't flat broke, but I didn't,
you know, have crazy money to start out with.
Who am I here with today?
James Dumlin.
I'm one of the founders
of the School of Hard Knocks,
which has become one of the biggest
business media channels in the entire world.
My two co-founders and I grew the channel to
over 10 million followers in just about three years.
And we've done over 3 billion views across social media.
So pretty crazy what can
happen in just a few years.
If you put your head down, you
focus, lock yourself in and see what happens.
Now I have to ask you, you ask
a lot of people how much money they make.
What was the most amount of money
that you've made in a single month?
Well, last month in December,
2024, my business did over $600,000 in revenue.
600,000, 600K.
What happened that month that you made $600,000?
Two words, vertical integration.
If you don't know them, look it
up, learn everything you can about them.
There was a time I interviewed
a gentleman in Scottsdale named Cody Sperber.
He owns four eight figure businesses.
And a piece of advice that he gave me was that a
savvy entrepreneur, he looks at his business and looks at one thing.
He looks at all the people that
are making money off of their efforts.
However, he doesn't know how to make money.
He doesn't know how to make money.
However, I actually added something to that
piece of advice that he gave me,
which is that a savvy entrepreneur looks at his business and doesn't just
look at all the people that are making money off of their efforts,
but all the different ways in which they can
be making money, which is exactly what we did.
We grew our channel to 10 million followers.
And instead of trying to go start a
whole bunch of different businesses and different industries,
we looked at the vertical that we had, which was the
10 million followers and the different ways that we could monetize.
So there were brand deals.
There was starting a content agency.
There was building a private community.
There was ad revenue.
There's all these different streams.
And we were able to vertically integrate and build
a multimillion dollar business in just a couple of years.
And in the month that you made over
$600,000, what was your biggest source of revenue?
So it's actually brand partnerships.
Content partnerships has been our biggest source of income.
How much of that $600,000 was profit?
Over half a million in profit.
Yeah, our business did over
$500,000 in profit this last month.
Now you built your business by going all
over the country, now all over the world,
just interviewing and asking
questions to millionaires and billionaires.
And you're interviewing billionaires off the street.
How many billionaires would you say that
you've interviewed over the last three years?
A lot.
So I would say in the last three years,
I've probably interviewed over 1,000 millionaires and over 15 billionaires.
15 billionaires that I know of.
15 billionaires?
15 billionaires.
Now, after interviewing over 15 billionaires and the
most successful people in the world across different industries,
what's the greatest lesson that you've learned?
What have you learned from this?
It's hard.
I get asked this question
all the time, by the way.
I'll tell you, it's really hard to
boil it down to just one thing.
However, after taking a lot of time to think
about this and analyzing all the interviews that I've done,
I've actually created and boiled it down to about five lessons
and takeaways that I personally had of the most common traits
and the most common things that I've seen the
most successful people from billionaires to Fortune 100 executives
to top athletes in the world to see
exactly what they do differently from everybody else.
You want them?
Give us the first lesson right now.
Okay.
Number one.
Billionaires.
They are the most successful people in the world.
They master the art of this one word.
If you don't know it, understand
it, learn everything you can about it.
Leverage.
They master the art of leverage and leverage in a
lot of different ways with people, with capital, with time.
Matter of fact, let's actually pull up an example
of an interview that I did recently with Shaquille O'Neal.
Shaquille O'Neal had 155 five guys.
He sold them all.
But I asked him, what was your
secret to scaling in the franchise model?
How did you scale out from one
to 10 to eventually 50, 100 and 100?
Yeah.
155 locations.
Here's what he had to say.
You own like 155 five guys at one point.
I sold them.
You sold them.
Yeah, I sold them.
What's your secret to scaling in the franchise model?
Just businesses in general.
The secret to scaling is one word.
Delegation.
I can't be in 155 places at
once, but I know somebody that can.
You heard it from him right there.
One word.
The secret to scaling is delegating, leveraging other people
to come in and be where you cannot be.
You cannot be in 1000 places at once.
See, the billionaires, the most hyper successful people.
They bring other people in to
be able to scale their businesses out.
Like I said, it's not just with people, though.
This is leverage also with capital, with money.
I have a client who owns several hundred million
dollars worth of real estate and our content agency.
And he said that you can tell how wealthy someone is by the
amount of debt that they're able to leverage or take on from banks.
Because wealthy people, they play
a different game than everybody else.
They understand how to borrow money to leverage that debt and to create more
wealth on it by understanding the ins and outs of the markets that they're in.
And that's what I'm talking about.
The markets that they're in, the people that are getting in on
the deals, the size of the transactions, the different whether it's residential, commercial.
More importantly, where I've seen this come up time and time
again and most commonly is when I ask people about negotiation.
For example, I interviewed the owner of some of the biggest banks
in all of Dallas, Texas, one of the biggest cities in the world.
I asked him for his best negotiation advice.
And here's what he had to say.
What do you do for
living out here in Dallas, Texas?
I run banks.
What was the most amount of money
that you ever made in a single year?
Oh, gosh.
Roughly 500 million a year.
Actually, I got to get one more.
Okay.
Negotiation.
It's a big component of businesses and closing deals.
And your businesses have done multiple nine figures.
You're at the table with some heavy hitters.
What's your best sales and negotiating advice for people trying to
get better at closing clients and closing deals in today's world?
Do you have a tactic for somebody that maybe they're running an
agency or a type of business where they're trying to close people?
What's your best negotiating advice for
people trying to close more deals?
Walk away.
The best deals I've done in my
life, I've walked away and they've come back.
You just heard it from him.
And let's not stop there.
How about Cal McNair?
I mentioned him earlier, the owner
of the Houston Texans, another multibillionaire.
I asked him.
What's his best advice on finding deals and negotiating?
This is what he had to say.
Excuse me, sir.
Question for you.
Is this your G-Wagon?
Yeah.
What do you do for living out in
Houston, Texas to be able to afford a G-Wagon?
Sorry?
What do you do for living out in Houston, Texas?
Work hard.
What industry are you in?
Football.
What are you doing exactly?
I own a football team.
What team?
Houston Texans.
You own the Houston Texans?
H-Town, baby.
Any negotiation advice?
Somebody, they struggle to close deals in business.
You've negotiated some massive deals.
What's the secret to negotiating?
You want to do it, but not that bad.
What do you mean by that?
You got to be able to walk away or what?
You got to be able to walk away.
Yeah.
At the same time, you're going
to be able to do it.
Absolutely.
Thank you, sir.
I appreciate you.
Thank you.
Did you hear that?
What did they both say?
You have to be willing
to walk away in a negotiation.
Understand this.
The person who is the most willing to walk
away from a deal in a negotiation will always
have the leverage.
You can never be desperate to get a deal done.
If you're desperate, then that's when deals go to shit.
Leverage with time, capital,
people, and overall creating value.
And if you're desperate, then
that's when deals go to shit.
Any scenario that you're in.
You know that's not taught in school, right?
What's number two?
Number two, they obsess over solving big problems.
And I actually first dove into this concept when I
interviewed a gentleman out in Houston who was a chiropractor.
But he owns one of the
largest medical practices in all of Texas.
And here's what he had to say about solving problems.
Excuse me, sir.
Question for you.
Have you ever been broke before?
No.
No?
Well, when I was a kid.
Not now.
What do you do for
living out here in Houston, Texas?
I'm a chiropractor.
Chiropractor?
What risk you took throughout your career?
Opening my own business.
How long have you been an entrepreneur for?
18 years.
18 years?
Almost 20 years.
What was the most amount of money
that you ever made in a single year?
1.7 million.
1.7 million dollars?
What took you from making six
to seven figures at your business?
Well, the key to any business is if you
give people what they want or need, you'll become successful.
If you solve people's problems, you'll become wealthy.
So learn what the problem is, solve the problem.
That's not my quote.
I'm not going to accept that.
But I practice that.
I apply that.
You heard it from him.
If you give people what they
want or need, you become rich.
But if you solve people's problems, you become wealthy.
Take that.
The biggest entrepreneurs, the biggest owners, the biggest business owners in the entire world, they go after massive markets and they solve
huge problems for not just a couple thousand, a couple hundred, but millions and billions of people if you really think about it.
Right?
I interviewed a gentleman, Zane Jan, who owns a multiple nine
figure, like a $300 million solar company out in Miami, Florida.
And he broke this down better
than I've ever heard explained before.
Here's what he had to say.
You're the CEO of one of the
largest solar companies in the entire country.
What has been the most amount of money
that you've ever made in a single year?
My business has done.
Did 149 million last year, and
we should do double that this year.
I believe if you want to be
a great entrepreneur, you have to solve problems.
Elon Musk once said, you get paid in direct
proportion to the size of the problems that you solve.
There weren't many problems that I thought that I could
solve that were very massive and big to the world.
When you look at a waiter,
what problem is a waiter solving?
Well, they're helping you get your favorite meal.
Maybe they're walking you through the
menu and they're bringing the food over.
Now, labor wise, that might be a hard job, but
mentally it takes a very small portion of your time.
And that's what I'm talking about.
That's what I'm talking about.
It's a very small portion of your IQ in
order to fulfill on that job and that duty.
So when I go up into a room of 100 people and say, hey, physically
and mentally, how possible is it for anyone in this room to be a waiter?
99 or 100 out of 100 people will
say that they can literally be a waiter.
Not that they want to
be, but that they can be.
Now, when I go into that same room of people and say, hey, how many of
you are confident that you can build a rocket ship that's going to go to Mars?
Zero out of 100 people will raise their hand.
You heard it from him.
If you take a waitress or even maybe a teacher,
for that matter, that teacher at the end of the year,
they're going to be attracting
100, maybe 200 people at most.
So they're solving problems, but
it's at a very small scale.
Whereas if you take somebody who's running a massive
multimillion dollar, billion dollar company, we brought up Elon Musk.
Well, look at what he's doing.
He's solving global energy with Tesla and renewable
energy, as well as interplanetary space travel with SpaceX.
So those are problems at a scale.
And that's why he's the richest, if not one of the wealthiest people
in the entire world, because of the proportion of the problems that he's solving.
I love that.
What's number three?
Number three.
Different.
The most successful people.
They attach themselves to other people
and they prioritize relationships over transactions.
See, there's a saying that stuck
with me the last couple of years.
I'm running this channel.
It's that people will take you places that money can't.
There's certain doors that money or anything
else won't be able to get you in.
The only thing that can simply get you
in those doors is by the route of connections.
And once you understand that relationship capital, that your net worth isn't calculated by the amount of
money that you have, but by the access to the amount of money that you have within
your network of people, that's when
you realize how successful you really are.
Everybody hears the saying your network is your net worth.
Well, that saying cannot be more true in today's world.
Let's hear it from Grant Cardone, who manages over $5 billion worth of real
estate at his company and raises hundreds of millions of dollars every single year.
Hear it from him.
You've got to attach yourself to
people because you cannot get money.
There's no money that will ever come to
another human being without going through another human being.
You're going to hold on to how
much money you got on you right now.
On me right now?
Yeah.
What you got on me?
None.
Just reaching.
You got nothing?
I don't have any cash on me right now.
You got a credit card.
You got something?
Let me see your credit card.
So you see, he's got some money on him.
Okay.
But what's the conduit?
The via between me and his credit card is him.
Now, two ways to get his credit card, right?
Okay.
I'm not going to show you
these numbers right here, but it's legit.
But I had to make contact with him to get his credit card, or
I got to wait for him to leave his wallet someplace and steal it.
I don't want to steal.
I'm not a thief because I
can only steal at one time.
But if I could create a
relationship with you, the way to money.
There you go.
The way to money.
You might see 200 already gone.
So the way to money is through people.
It's not through a bank.
You heard it right there.
Anytime wealth is transferred, a transaction happens.
It's impossible for it to not
go from one person to the other.
I want to give another one right here.
Thomas Kehinde, a multimillionaire insurance
broker out in Miami, Florida.
When he told me this
right here, this changed my life.
In the money business and finance, whenever wealth is transferred
from one person to another, there's somebody in the middle
there.
There's somebody in the middle there.
That's helping transfer their wealth.
Well, that person in the middle always becomes wealthy.
Hear it from him.
How can somebody become a millionaire in 2024?
I want to think about this for a second.
Anytime wealth is transferred from one hand to the other, somebody
is in the middle that is helping to transfer the wealth.
Whoever that person is also becomes wealthy.
I genuinely cannot stress this point enough.
I've interviewed some of the wealthiest people that have ever worked on
Wall Street, and they never even placed a financial trade in their lives.
They got rich off of
a handshake because they simply made
the right introductions, were able to connect the
right people, or just simply brokering a deal.
And that's a concept that a lot of people, they have this misconception that in order for them to create
extreme amounts of wealth, that they have to be so talented at learning how to code or develop some crazy software.
When in reality, if you just understand people, how to build rapport, how to build relationships, how
to establish those connections, you can become wealthy just by doing that, just off of a simple handshake.
I want to leave one more with us today.
I want to go back to
Steven Klubeck, the Beverly Hills multibillionaire.
Here's what he had to say.
How old were you when you became a millionaire?
You have to ask a millionaire.
What do you mean?
I'm a billionaire.
You're a billionaire?
Yeah.
How old were you when you became a billionaire?
Oh, in my 50s.
How important were relationships for you?
Relationships are always very important.
But a matter of fact, you got to stay out
of one zip code, the zip code of bad people.
If they're around your life, make them go away.
And there you have it.
From once again, not just me, but a multibillionaire.
Let me ask you a question.
Yeah.
Do you have real dreams?
Yes.
Is there a shortcut to them?
No.
Yes, there is.
The shortcut is mentorship.
And let me tell you this.
Over the last three years in
building a multibillion dollar network of people
that I know and I'm connected to
building this channel to 10 million followers was
through that one concept of mentorship
and when I first started this channel,
my partners and I, we originally had wanted
to go figure out, go learn how the most
successful people got to where
they were in different industries.
But it eventually grew to the point where
we wanted to connect as many people as
possible with the most successful people in
the world that we have the ability
to interview and actually build relationships with.
And that's why a couple of months ago,
I actually launched and created one of the
largest entrepreneur communities in the entire
world called the School of Mentors,
where every single week I host live
mentorship calls for the people that join
the community, they have the ability to
hop on these calls and ask their questions
directly to the multimillionaires and
the billionaires that I'm interviewing.
Ask them anything.
Nothing's off limits.
Ask them about different skills, like how
to sell, how to negotiate like a billionaire
word, for example, Steven Klubeck.
He was a mentor on a call.
He taught our community how to negotiate
like a billionaire word, how to find
investors who did not take money from
because not all money is good money.
We had people like Todd Napola
who owns several hundred million dollars worth
of real estate. He taught our community how
to find deals, how to get access to capital
if you don't have any money and how
to invest in real estate without having any
money to your name. Or how
about the former CEO of 7-Eleven?
He came and taught our community leadership and how
to work your way up in the business world.
And I'll give you one more.
Sean Mike, he took a company to three
billion in sales in a matter of a
few years. He taught our community the art of
sales and how to scale from not just a six,
but to eventually a seven,
eight and a nine figure business.
These are mentors that we have on the calls
every single week where you guys will get direct access
to them to ask them any questions about how to
go from point A to point B in your business.
So if you were watching right now and
you want to join this community at the lowest,
the price will ever be.
Matter of fact, I'll tell you, you
can join right now for seven days.
Money back guarantee.
You join and it's completely free for those seven days.
If you don't like it, money back guarantee.
But I guarantee you, if you give
it a shot, you hop on those calls,
you go indulge in some of
the content that's in that community.
You will never, ever regret it.
So I can't wait to see
all you guys inside of the community.
If you want to join, go down to
the link in the description of this video.
The School of Mentors.
Can't wait to see you inside.
Let's get back to these lessons.
Let's go to number four.
They are masters at selling themselves.
See, I've learned I learned this
statistic recently that 75% of billionaires,
they started off in some form of direct sales.
And there's a gentleman that I mentioned before.
Todd.
Napoleon.
He owns a couple hundred million dollars
worth of real estate out in South Florida.
And he gave me this piece of advice that
really stuck with me about
the world's most successful people.
You're always selling.
And anybody who thinks you're going to
be in business without selling is sadly
mistaken, you will sell forever and I
will assure you, Elon Musk, Mark Zuckerberg,
the richest guys on the planet
are still selling themselves all day long.
Or you're out of business.
You heard it from him.
The world's most successful people are
still selling themselves to this very day.
And they don't stop doing it.
If Elon Musk was in this room
with us right now, if he wanted $10,000, $20,000, $100,000
from us, whether we had it to our names or not,
we by all means are going to find a way
to go get him that money because of who he is,
because of the person that he's become, because
of the way that he's able to sell himself.
Take the most successful people.
Mark Cuban, Gary Vee.
They can go into any company headquarters, Coca-Cola, and go land a $50 million
deal just off the premise of the way that they're able to sell themselves.
Being able to storytell.
Look at Steve Jobs and how
he was able to present Apple.
It's not Apple today if it wasn't for Steve Jobs and his
ability to storytell, to sell the company and be able to sell himself.
So you need to learn how to sell just as much
as it's important to have product knowledge, learning how to close.
You need to be able to learn how to sell yourself
because that is going to take you further than anything in sales.
You got to learn how to sell.
Now you've interviewed over
a thousand millionaires and billionaires.
Give us that fifth lesson right here.
Number five, arguably one of the most
underrated tools, billionaires and the most successful people.
They think in decades.
Not in days.
Let's hear it from a Miami banker who
owns the largest bank in all of Miami.
Question for you, sir.
Is this your Rolls Royce?
Yes.
And what do you do for living out of
Miami, Florida to be able to afford a Rolls Royce?
Investment banking.
Real estate.
How long have you been in finance for?
35 years.
Have you ever met a billionaire before?
I know a lot of billionaires.
What's that?
You know a lot of billionaires.
That's my job.
Are you a billionaire?
Well, you can say that.
Yeah?
Yeah.
It makes you feel good, right?
You're a billionaire.
Oh, you can say that?
Yeah.
That's incredible.
How can somebody become a billionaire like you?
I'll tell you.
Tell him.
Seven days, 14 hours a day, 35 years.
Master of one.
35 years.
But I don't want to just leave it at that.
How about Dean Graziosi?
Let's hear what he has
to say about making quick money.
What was the most amount of money
that you ever made in a single year?
I won't share that, but my
brands have done over a billion dollars.
Your brands have done over a billion dollars?
Yeah.
So a lot of people watch this video, right?
If you can comment below, I would love for
any of you, any of you, to write down how
you got rich for hardly doing anything, got rich fast.
I bet you won't find one comment.
No.
No one gets rich overnight.
Do some people get lucky?
Is there somebody who bought
crypto at $1,000, didn't even know?
And now it's, of course.
And that's one tenth of one tenth of 1%.
And you know, because you're interviewing
successful people, you know when you get
behind the scenes, they put
in the time, they failed miserably.
They questioned themselves.
Family thought they were nuts.
Their friends thought they were crazy.
They had to sacrifice certain things.
That's how you get to that next level.
Just like he said, nobody gets rich overnight.
This is a long game.
You got to think in 10, 20, 30, 40 years.
All these people, Jeff Bezos was running Amazon.
He didn't step down as the CEO until like
20 or 30 years after he was running the company.
Let's pull up Eric Spofford, who
sold a business for over $115 million.
Listen to what he has to
say about patience and delayed gratification.
What has been the most amount of money
that you've ever made in a single year?
I cracked over $100 million in one year.
Hell yeah.
Let me give you another little golden nugget.
This is where most of you guys fuck up.
You guys think it happens fast and
then you don't look at the long term.
You need to have.
Macro patience and micro urgency.
What you guys have is micro patience and macro urgency.
And what I mean by that is you need to
know that this is going to take a long time.
People look at my life and they don't see the 17 fucking
years that happened before I was out here in Miami living this life.
And so they miscalibrate on
how long it's going to take.
They think it's going to happen faster than it is.
You need to commit to this
for a long period of time.
That's macro patience and then have micro urgency.
Every single fucking.
Day you give it absolutely
everything that you have to give.
Let's fucking go, Eric.
Come on, bro.
Hear that again.
Macro patience and micro urgency.
You need to understand that this is going to take
a long time to get to where you want to be.
But that doesn't take away from the fact that in the short
term, you need to be relentless about your pursuit of becoming successful.
Because if you're not and somebody is going to come up within
your space and it's going to overtake you, pour gas down their throats.
No matter what business you're in, you
need to be relentless in the short term.
But have the mindset.
That it is going to take a long time.
This is a long game.
Business is not an overnight thing.
But if you can apply that and have that principle and understand the
importance of taking action in the short term, then it will all work out.
And one more advice that I really want to add on here that I think
is very important that isn't talked about enough is from a gentleman out in Scottsdale.
I interviewed named Brian North.
Roll it.
Your real estate brokerage.
What's the most amount of money that you
guys have sold in revenue in one year?
$1.4 billion.
Build a good reputation.
My dad always says it takes 20 years to
build a good reputation and five minutes to kill it.
It takes a long.
Time.
Years.
5, 10, 20 years to build a solid reputation
with people and only five minutes to kill it.
So again, the fifth greatest lesson that I've learned is the importance
of that patience and understanding to not think in days but decades.
All right.
Now, I know you said
that there were only five lessons.
Is there any way you have one more
bonus for us before we leave here today?
Give us one more thing that you've learned
from interviewing the most successful people in the world.
One more bonus lesson.
If you have one.
You need one more.
Okay.
Well, one thing that I've learned, and if you've ever consumed any of my content, you'll probably start to realize
that the most successful people in the world, I can guarantee you a lot of them, they came from nothing.
But when they get to a point of success, you can take everything away from them,
and they have it in their mindset that they know that they can make it all back.
Let's take, for example, I interviewed the
richest Indian man who's living in Dubai.
Here's what he had to say about that when
I asked him if I took everything away from him.
If he lost everything, could he make it all back?
What was the most amount of money
that you've made in a single year?
10 billion dirhams.
Are you a billionaire?
I suppose I'm a billionaire.
You're a billionaire.
Yeah.
What's your name?
My name is Rizwan Sajjan.
If you lost everything tomorrow,
could you make it all back?
If you put me in the
African jungle also, I'll make also there.
I will sell the property to the animals over there.
Yeah.
He said he would sell property to animals.
So you heard it from him.
You could put him in the jungle
and he would be selling properties to animals.
And that's something that I think
is very important to note on.
And again, if you've consumed any
of my content, you'll see this.
Time and time again, they have
this unwavering belief in themselves that
nothing's impossible, that if you take
everything away from them because they
have the mindset and the skill sets once
you can take their capital, you can take
their family, you can take everything, but
once they have that ability to build,
they will build it back and they will
build it back ten times bigger than ever before.
I love it.
Well, I got to say, it was
a pleasure having you here with us today.
Thank you so much for having me, man.
I really enjoyed the conversation.
It's great to be here.
Where can everybody find you at?
So the School of Hard
Knox on all platforms, a lot of you
maybe have seen the content before, but yeah,
check out the School of Hard Knocks
and like I mentioned earlier in the video,
you guys be sure to become a member
of my private community, the School of Mentors.
Like I said, guys, of all the lessons
that I've said, the one thing that's going to
get you to where you need to
be in your business financially, your career is
through mentorship, and I'm bringing you
guys every single week the world's most
successful people to directly
answer your questions about anything.
Sales, marketing, scaling, leadership, hiring, everything.
Coming directly to you on live calls every
single week at the most affordable price of any
mentorship program that I've ever seen in my entire life.
To join, like we said earlier, go to the
link down in the description of this video to join
the School of Mentors today.
I can't wait to see all of
you guys on the inside of this community.
So yeah, that's where you can find me at.
Awesome.
Guys, be sure to like and subscribe for
amazing content we've got coming every single week
and click right here to watch our
full interview with business mogul Patrick Bet-David.
I can't wait to see
you guys in the next video.
Bye.